Finding Aid for the Stafford Leak Warren Papers LSC.0987
UCLA Library Special Collections
- III. Operation Crossroads Papers.
  - Photographs, Operation Crossroads, With Cover Note., July 25, 1946.; 23 items:
    - 8. 7/DB/CR/PBM(U)/178/403/11. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - 9. 7/DB/CR/PBM(U)/178/403/12. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - 10. 7/DB/CR/PBM(U)/178/403/13. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - 11. 7/DB/CR/PBM(U)/178/403/14. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - 12. 7/DB/CR/PBM(U)/178/403/15. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - 13. 7/DB/CR/PBM(U)/178/403/16. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - 14. 7/DB/CR/PBM(U)/178/403/17. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - 15. 7/DB/CR/PBM(U)/178/403/18. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - 16. 7/DB/CR/PBM(U)/178/403/19. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - 17. 7/DB/CR/PBM(U)/178/403/20. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - 18. AB/CR/654/2416/1. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - 19. AB/CR/654/2416/8. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - 20. AB/CR/654/2646/5. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - 21. AB/CR/654/2416/10. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - 22. AB/CR/654/2597/3. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - 23. AB/CR/181/2846/4. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Photographs, Operation Crossroads., undated; 188 items:
      - 1. 639/-1. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 2. 639/0. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 3. 639/1. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 4. 639/2. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 5. 639/3. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 6. 639/4. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 7. 639/5. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 8. 639/6. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 9. 639/7. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 10. 639/8. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 11. 639/9. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 12. 639/10. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 13. 639/11. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 14. 639/12. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 15. 639/13. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 16. 639/14. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 17. 639/15. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 18. 639/16. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 19. 639/17. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 20. 639/18. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 21. 639/19. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 22. 639/20. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 23. 639/21. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 24. 639/22. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 25. 639/23. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 26. 639/24. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 27. 639/25. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 28. 639/26. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 29. 639/27. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 30. 639/28. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 31. 639/29. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 32. 639/30. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 33. 639/31. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 34. 639/32. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 35. 639/33. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 36. 639/34. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 37. 639/35. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 38. 639/36. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 39. 639/37. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 40. 639/38. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 41. 639/39. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 42. 639/40. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 43. 639/41. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 44. 639/43. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 45. 639/44. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 46. 639/45. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 47. 639/46. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 48. 639/47. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 49. 639/48. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 50. 639/49. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 51. 639/50. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 52. 639/51. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 53. 639/52. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 54. 639/53. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 55. 639/54. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 56. 639/55. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 57. 639/56. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 58. 639/57. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 59. 639/58. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 60. 639/59. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 61. 639/60. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 62. 639/61. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 63. 639/62. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 64. 639/63. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 65. 639/64. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 66. 639/65. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 67. 639/66. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 68. 639/67. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 69. 639/68. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 70. 639/69. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 71. 639/70. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 72. 639/71. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 73. 639/72. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 74. 639/73. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 75. 639/74. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 76. 639/75. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 77. 639/76. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 78. 639/77. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 79. 639/78. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 80. 639/79. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 81. 639/80. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 82. 639/81. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 83. 639/82. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 84. 639/83. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 85. 639/84. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 86. 639/85. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 87. 639/86. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 88. 639/87. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 89. 639/88. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 90. 639/89. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 91. 639/90. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 92. 639/91. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 93. 639/92. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 94. 639/93. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 95. 639/94. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 96. 639/95. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 97. 639/96. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 98. 639/97. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 99. 639/98. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 100. 639/99. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 101. 639/100. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 102. 639/101. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 103. 639/102. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 104. 639/103. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 105. 639/104. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 106. 639/105. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 107. 639/106. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 108. 639/107. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 109. 639/108. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 110. 639/109. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 111. 639/110. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 112. 639/111. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 113. 639/112. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 114. 639/113. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 115. 639/114. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 116. 639/115. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 117. 639/116. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 118. 639/117. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 119. 639/118. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 120. 639/119. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 121. 639/120. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 122. 639/121. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 123. 639/122. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 124. 639/123. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 125. 639/124. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 126. 639/125. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 127. 639/126. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 128. 639/127. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 129. 639/128. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 130. 639/129. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 131. 639/130. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 132. 639/131. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 133. 639/132. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 134. 639/133. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 135. 639/134. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 136. 639/135. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 137. 639/136. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 138. 639/137. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 139. 639/138. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 140. 639/139. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 141. 639/140. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 142. 639/141. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 143. 639/142. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 144. 639/143. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 145. 639/144. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 146. 639/145. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 147. 639/146. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 148. 639/147. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 149. 639/148. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 150. 639/149. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 151. 639/150. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 152. 639/151. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 153. 639/152. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 154. 639/153. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 155. 639/154. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 156. 639/155. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 157. 639/156. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 158. 639/157. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 159. 639/158. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 160. 639/159. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 161. 639/160. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 162. 639/161. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 163. 639/162. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 164. 639/163. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 165. 639/164. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 166. 639/165. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 167. 639/166. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 168. 639/167. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 169. 639/168. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 170. 639/169. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 171. 639/170. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 172. 639/171. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 173. 639/172. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 174. 639/173. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 175. 639/174. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 176. 639/175. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 177. 639/176. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 178. 639/177. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 179. 639/178. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 180. 639/179. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 181. 639/180. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 182. 639/181. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 183. 639/182. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 184. 639/183. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 185. 639/184. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 186. 639/185. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 187. 639/186. (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 188. 639/187. (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Photographic Prints and Negatives, Operation Crossroads., undated, 1946.; 55 items:
    - 1-4. 3 negatives, Damsel fish and algae., undated; (4 items including envelope). (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - 5-7. 2 negatives, Surgeon fish., undated; (3 items including envelope). (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - 7-21. Prints of negatives, three or four exposures on each print., undated (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - 22-36. Prints of negatives, one exposure on each print., undated (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - 37. Photograph, cloud formation., undated (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - 38-54. Negatives marked: Films., undated; (18 items including envelope). (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - 55. Mounted photograph, with cover note, radiograph of algae collected in Bikini Lagoon by Dr. W.R. Taylor., August 7, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Assorted Letters., November 1946-February 1947.; 44 items:
    - 1. Letter, D.L. Collins, Victoreen Instrument Company to SLW., November 29, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 2. Note, Herbert Mermagen, University of Rochester, to SLW., November 29, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 3. Letter, Harris, Jefferson Hospital to SLW., November 30, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 4. Copy letter, SLW to Captain Lyon., November 30, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 5. Copy letter, SLW to Dr. M.L. Pool., November 30, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 6. Copy letter, SLW to Dr. Harold Hodge, Strong Memorial Hospital., November 30, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 7. Copy letter, SLW to Dr. Herbert Stockinger, Medical School Annex., November 30, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 8. Copy letter, SLW to Dr. Herman Pearse, Strong Memorial Hospital., November 30, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 9. Copy letter, SLW to Fred Esler., November 30, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 10. Copy letter, SLW to Colonel Alfred de Lorimer., November 30, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 11. Copy letter, SLW to Dr. Robert R. Newell., November 30, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 12. Copy letter, SLW to Dr. J. Hamilton, Crocker Laboratories., November 30, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 13. Copy letter, SLW to Dr. A.H. Dowdy, Medical School Annex., November 30, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 14. Copy letter, SLW to Colonel James P. Cooney., November 30, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 15. Letter, Ralph D. Ross to SLW., December 1, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 16. Letter, Lauren R. Donaldson, Director, Applied Fisheries, University of Washington School of Fisheries to SLW., December 2, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 17. Letter, Mrs. Marion M. Norman, secretary to J.G. Hamilton, M.D., University of California to SLW., December 2, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 18. Letter, Hymer L. Friedell, M.D., University Hospitals of Cleveland to SLW., December 5, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 19. Letter, Howard L. Andrews, physicist, to SLW., December 19, 1946. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 20. Copy letter, SLW to Kenneth Scott, University of California., February 3, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 21. Copy letter, SLW to Dr. R.E. Lapp, Scientific Advisor., February 3, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 22. Copy letter, SLW to Colonel James P. Cooney., February 3, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 23. Copy letter, SLW to Captain George Lyon., February 3, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 24. Copy letter, SLW to Dr. Hymer L. Friedell, University Hospitals of Cleveland., February 3, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 25. Copy letter, SLW to SLW [sic]., February 3, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 26. Copy letter, SLW to Dr. Joseph Hamilton., February 3, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 27. Copy letter, SLW to Dr. Herman Pearse, University of Rochester School of Medicine and Dentistry., February 3, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 28. Letter, M.L. Pool, Professor of Physics, Ohio State University, to Robert J. Buettner, Medical School Annex, University of Rochester., February 4, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 29. Letter, D.L. Collins, Laboratory Director, Victoreen Instrument Company to Dr. Fred A. Bryan, Atomic Energy Commission., February 3, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 30. Letter, A.A. Zuehlke, Engineering Department, Taylor Instrument Company to Dr. Fred A. Bryan., February 5, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 31. Letter, Howard L. Andrews to SLW., February 6, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 32. Letter, M.L. Pool, Ohio State University to SLW., February 7, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 33. Note, (Mrs. R.R.) Jeannette Newell to SLW., February 8, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 34. Letter, Rodney Stoltz, 1st Lt., M.C., AVS, Oak Ridge Hospital to Fred., February 10, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 35. Letter, Ralph D. Ross to Dr. Fred A. Bryan., February 10, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 36. Rough note, Baker Kodachromes, from G. Dessauer., undated (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 37. Letter, Joseph G. Hoffman to SLW., February 11, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 38. Letter, Lauren R. Donaldson, University of Washington to Dr. Fred A. Bryan., February 12, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 39. Letter, Gordon A. Nicoll, M.D. to SLW., February 17, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 40. Letter, Richard H. Hodges, Technical Analysis Unit, Joint Crossroads Committee to Dr. Fred Bryan., February 17, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 41. Copy letter, Fred A. Bryan, M.D. to Ensign Richard H. Hodges, Technical Analysis Unit, Joint Crossroads Committee., February 19, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 42. Copy letter, Fred A. Bryan, M.D. to Dr. Gordon Nicoll., February 19, 1947. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 43. Copy list, Declassification Panel Action., April 20, 1950. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 44. Copy letter, Chief, Armed Forces, Special Weapons Project to Robert J. Buettner, University of California., undated (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - SLW notebook with loose rough notes included., January-February 1946.; 1 item. (Box 83, Folder 4)
- IV. Additional Material Relating to Nuclear Energy and Bombs.
  See also Box 156 and oversize packages 6 and 13 below.
  - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission files, including copy reports and correspondence., December 1946-April 1948. (Box 84)
  - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission files, including copy reports and correspondence., May 1948-1950. (Box 85)
  - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission printed technical reports. (Box 86, Box 87)
  - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission annual reports., 1959-1965. (Box 88)
  - Various U.S. Government publications, mostly Congressional hearings., 1950s-1960s. (Box 89, Box 90, Box 91, Box 92, Box 93, Box 94, Box 95, Box 96)
  - Contents of filing cabinet drawer labelled, Atomic Energy, a) Washington; b) UCLA (General Contract #12) - Laboratory for Nuclear Medicine. (Box 97, Box 98, Box 99, Box 100, Box 101)
  - Correspondence and papers, mostly relating to SLW's Postwar atomic energy work. Includes letter from Harold C. Urey., (folder 3). (Box 102)
  - Various printed materials. (Box 103)
  - U.S. Senate hearings, Special Committee on Atomic Energy, vol.1-13., 1945. (Box 104)
  - U.S. Senate hearings, Atomic Energy Commission, vol.1-9., 1946. (Box 104)
  - Atomic Energy Commission materials: semi-annual reports, issues of AEC News, and material relating to Dresden Atomic Plant. (Box 105)
    (See also Box 156 below)
  - Glass slides relating to Atomic Energy Commission training course for physicians. (Box 106)
  - Atomic Support Agency technical progress reports. Air Pollution Control District (Los Angeles County) reports. (Box 107)
    See also Boxes 161-177 below.
  - Contents of filing cabinet drawer labelled, The Bomb. Almagordo, Manhattan Engineering District, Japan, Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, Bikini, JTF-One, Post-war, Atomic Energy Commission. (Box 108, Box 109)
    See also Sections 2-3 above.
  - Technical reports and journals relating to the atomic bomb and radiation. (Box 110)
    Includes Manhattan Engineering District report, Photographs of atomic bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki; Hiroshima Peace Museum booklet; Hiroshima under Atomic Attack; and copy leaflets dropped on Japan in connection with atomic bombs (in Japanese, with attached English translations).
    See also Section 2 above.
  - Contents of filing cabinet drawer labelled, Civil Defence. a) California State. b) American Medical Association Council. c) Federal. d) Veterans Administration. (Box 111, Box 112, Box 113, Box 114, Box 115)
    Box 111 includes reports on Nagasaki and aerial photographs.
    Box 112 includes material relating to the Medical Advisory Committee to the Atomic Energy Commission, 1946-1947, Operation Crossroads, and the University of California medical research program.
    Box 113 includes material about Operation Crossroads.
  - Transcripts of session proceedings of the first Conference on Long-range Biomedical and Psychosocial effects of Nuclear War, New York Academy of Sciences Interdisciplinary Communications Program., January 18-21, 1967. (Box 116)
  - Transcripts of session proceedings of the second Conference on the Long-range Biomedical and Psychosocial Effects of Nuclear War, New York Academy of Sciences Interdisciplinary Communications Program., October 4-7, 1967. (Box 117)
  - Transcripts of session proceedings of the third Conference on Long-range Biomedical and Psychosocial Effects of Nuclear War, New York Academy of Sciences Interdisciplinary Communications Program., March 20-23, 1968. (Box 118)
  - U.S. State Department and other government agencies' publications relating to broad issues in American foreign policy, including the development of nuclear energy and communism., circa 1948-1953. (Box 119)
  - Various publications, including U.S. Army Medical Service Historical Unit reports and documents relating to the Manhattan Engineering Project and radiation. (Box 120)
- V. Special Assistant to the President for Mental Retardation.
  - Papers. (Box 121, Box 122, Box 123, Box 124, Box 125, Box 126, Box 127, Box 128, Box 129, Box 130, Box 131, Box 132, Box 133, Box 134, Box 135)
    3 desk diaries in Box 121 were found in the papers of Dr. Warren's first wife, Viola Warren (Department of Special Collections numbered collection 1322) which also includes (Box 19) correspondence, mostly social, photographs, clippings and ephemera about the Warrens' residence in Washington, D.C.
- VI. Various Assignments and Consultant Projects.
  - Materials relating to computer programs for libraries. (Box 136, Box 137, Box 138, Box 139, Box 140, Box 141, Box 142)
  - Materials relating to a survey of small medical schools. (Box 143, Box 144, Box 145, Box 146, Box 147, Box 148, Box 149, Box 150, Box 151, Box 152, Box 153, Box 154, Box 155, Box 156)
    Box 156 also contains miscellaneous printed materials, including: Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory. A Review of criticality Accidents. Atomic Energy Commission, 1967.
  - Architectural plans, Los Angeles County Harbour General Hospital. (Box 157)
  - Materials relating to medical education and research. (Box 158, Box 159, Box 160)
- VII. Research Materials, as Grouped by Stafford L. Warren.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  Most material in this section was removed from filing cabinet drawers which were labelled as indicated in inverted commas; it includes printed items, photographs and clippings.
  - Air pollution. a) General. b) California Air Resources Board. c) Los Angeles County Air Pollution Control District. (Box 161, Box 162, Box 163, Box 164, Box 165, Box 166, Box 167, Box 168, Box 169, Box 170, Box 171, Box 172, Box 173, Box 174, Box 175, Box 176)
    See also Box 107 above.
  - Air pollution studies. (Box 177)
  - Cancer. (Box 178)
    See also Box 220 below.
  - Craters and related matters. (Box 179, Box 180)
  - Craters. a) Bellamy. b) Paper. c) Science tear sheets. (Box 181, Box 182, Box 183, Box 184, Box 185, Box 186, Box 187)
  - Environmental issues, printed materials. Electron microscope and X-ray. (Box 188)
  - Electron microscope and X-ray. (Box 189)
  - Geological studies. a) Evolution of species. b) Radiation background (cosmic, clay, granite). c) Radiation biology. d) Earth geology. (Box 190, Box 191, Box 192, Box 193, Box 194, Box 195, Box 196)
  - Mice and chicken research. (Box 197, Box 198, Box 199)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 200, Box 201, Box 202)
  - Rheumatoid arthritis. (Box 203, Box 204, Box 205, Box 206, Box 207, Box 208, Box 209, Box 210)
    Box 203 contains papers from the 1970s.
    Box 207 contains mostly printed items but includes some letters.
    Box 209 contains patient records, 1972-1975 (restricted).
    Box 210 includes material relating to veterans' affairs.
    See also oversize package 8 below.
  - References. (Box 211, Box 212, Box 213, Box 214, Box 215, Box 216)
    Arranged alphabetically:
    Box 211: A - C
    Box 212: C - G
    Box 213: G - O
    Box 214: O - P
    Box 215: P - R
    Box 216: R - Z
  - Recent projects. a) Emeriti Institute. b) Organisations. (Box 217, Box 218, Box 219, Box 220)
    Box 220 also includes material on cancer.
    See also Box 178 above.
  - Space. a) Lunar origin. b) Astrogeology. c) NASA etc. (Box 221, Box 222, Box 223, Box 224)
    Box 224 includes material on information retrieval, including NASA projects.
  - Notes, photographs and printed material. (Box 225, Box 226, Box 227, Box 228, Box 229, Box 230, Box 231, Box 232, Box 233, Box 234, Box 235, Box 236, Box 237, Box 238, Box 239, Box 240, Box 241, Box 242, Box 243, Box 244, Box 245, Box 246, Box 247, Box 248, Box 249, Box 250, Box 251, Box 252)
    Box 225 includes files, 1940s.
    Box 226 includes diaries.
    Box 227 contains photographs, diaries and files.
    Box 228 includes later manuscripts and articles of SLW.
    Box 232 contains notebooks and miscellaneous printed materials.
    Box 233 contains photograph files.
    Box 234 contains smears (glass slides).
    Box 235 contains smears (glass slides), a notebook and 35mm. film.
    Box 237 contains smears (glass slides) and notebooks.
    Box 238 contains notebooks and 16mm. motion picture film.
    Boxes 239-240 contain card index of references and notebooks.
    Box 241 contains manuscript draft of a book sent to SLW: Charles V. Kidd. American Universities and Federal Research.
    Boxes 242-246 contain slides.
    Boxes 247-250 contain pictorial material (contents of a filing cabinet drawer labelled, Pix.).
    Box 252 contains photograph albums, prints and slides relating to medical experimments.
    (See also Boxes 253-260 below)
- VIII. Writings by Stafford L. Warren.
  See also Box 228 above.
  - Rough drafts. (Box 253, Box 254, Box 255, Box 256)
  - Manuscripts. Also includes miscellaneous printed materials, mostly copies of The American Journal of Gastroenterology. (Box 257)
  - Contents of a container labelled, SLW manuscripts, UCLA., circa 1978. (Box 258)
  - Bound volumes of collected reprints by SLW and unbound reprints by SLW in collaboration with others., 1922-1939. (Box 259)
  - Reprints by SLW in collaboration with others. (Box 260)
- IX. Miscellaneous Materials.
  See also oversize package 10 below and the papers of Dr. Warren's first wife, Viola Warren (Department of Special Collections numbered collection 1322).
  - Index cards to part of the Warren papers; index cards containing bibliographical information. (Box 261, Box 262, Box 263)